A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Projects, Series L FA348
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - State Department - Exhibit, Secretary Marshall, 1947-1950 (Box 154, Folder 1540)
  Correspondence re "The Marshall Affair", which dealt with the withdrawal of the State Department exhibition from Circulation. Discussion of the MoMA position and letter to Secretary G. C. Marshall. Clippings, correspondence re loan of two paintings, 1948. Exhibit in Central America and establishment of Fund to pay for MoMA publications.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Statement on Modern Art, 1949-1950 (Box 154, Folder 1541)
  Joint statement by MoMA, Institute of Contemporary Art, Whitney Museum. Printed statement; clippings; drafts; memos re statement; letters discussing advisability of joint statement. MoMA Executive Committee disapproval.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Steichen, Captain Edward, 1954-1969 (Box 154, Folder 1542)
  NAR letters to Steichen in honor of his 75th and 90th birthdays.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Stieglitz Collection, 1947-1948 (Box 154, Folder 1543)
  Disagreements over Miss O'Keeffe's and MoMA's commitments in publishing catalogue of Stieglitz's work. Museum's use of the collection.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Study of Directorates of Museums, 1940 (Box 154, Folder 1544)
  Listings of Directors of U.S. museums and their occupations.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Subscriptions, General Correspondence, 1933-1948 (Box 154, Folder 1545)
  Fund-raising activities. Plans for approaching large donors. Drive to raise $1,000,000 endowment to secure Lizzie Bliss collection. Annual Budget drives. List of people contacted and subscriptions made. Correspondents include Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Suggestions, 1952 (Box 154, Folder 1546)
  Suggestion that MoMA buy and develop a particular piece of property on Fifth Avenue. Blueprint and photos.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Sweeney, James Johnson, 1946-1953 (Box 154, Folder 1547)
  Resigned as Director of Painting & Sculpture on 1946 reorganization. Letters re resignation; press comment. No real discussion of issues at stake in this file.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Taxes, Admissions, Contributions, Gifts of Art, 1948-1969 (Box 154, Folder 1548)
  Clippings re tax exemptions for admission to MoMA. Tax status of other non-profit organization. NAR's letters to Senators on Finance Committee. Correspondence re the nature of the tax laws.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Taxes, Admissions, Contributions, Gifts of Art - 30% Tax Ruling, 1959-1964 (Box 154, Folder 1549)
  Memos re tax laws and deduction of 30%.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Television Archive of the Arts, 1967 (Box 155, Folder 1550)
  List of films on Art; press release on formation of archive.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Television and Radio, 1947-1960 (Box 155, Folder 1551)
  Clipping on children's TV show on art. Memos on television project. NBC show on Museum script. Letters re Radio broadcasts over WNEW from MoMA; proposed television series; press release re television program on visual art. Rockefeller Brothers Fund contribution for MoMA's television program and research, 1953. Reprint of article on art and television. Coverage of exhibits and protest, 1960.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - General, 1936-1970 (Box 155, Folder 1552)
  Selection of Trustees. Resignations. NAR's personal contact with trustees.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Report by Ad Hoc Planning Committee, 1969 (Box 155, Folder 1553)
  A conceptual framework study.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Reports (138.614), 1935-1965 (Box 155, Folder 1554)
  1935 Report to Carnegie Foundation.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Committee Members, 1951-1970 (Box 155, Folder 1555)
  List of Members.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Reception, Committee on Art Education, 1948 (Box 156, Folder 1556)
  Held for art educators in New York Area. Modern artists invited.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Contributions, Correspondence, Memos - Overall, 1945-1959 (Box 156, Folder 1557)
  NAR letters to trustees, asking for contributions. Results of NAR canvassing.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Trustees' Meetings - Meeting of 4/8/48, 1948-1952 (Box 156, Folder 1558)
  NAR notes and memos on selected trustee Minutes. Tribute to Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Trustees' Meetings - Meeting of Trustees and Corporation Meeting, November 16, 1950 (Box 156, Folder 1559)
  NAR notes and memos on selected trustee Minutes.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Trustees' Meetings - Meeting of 3/13/52, March 13, 1952 (Box 156, Folder 1560)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Trustees' Meetings - Meeting of 10/9/52, October 9, 1952 (Box 156, Folder 1561)
  NAR notes and memos on selected trustee Minutes. NAR notes.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Trustees' Meetings - Meeting of 12/13/51, December 13, 1951 (Box 156, Folder 1562)
  NAR notes and memos on selected trustee Minutes. NAR material.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Trustees' Meetings - Meeting of 10/11/51, October 11, 1951 (Box 156, Folder 1563)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Trustees' Meetings - Meeting of 12/8/49, December 8, 1949 (Box 156, Folder 1564)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Barr, Alfred, 1950 (Box 156, Folder 1565)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Bartlett, Frederic Clay, 1951 (Box 156, Folder 1566)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Bliss, Mrs. Robert Woods, 1947-1953 (Box 156, Folder 1567)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Clark, Stephen, 1942-1960 (Box 156, Folder 1568)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Colin, Ralph F., 1949-1954 (Box 156, Folder 1569)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Crane, Mrs. W. Murray, 1950 (Box 156, Folder 1570)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - d'Harnoncourt, Rene, 1950 (Box 156, Folder 1571)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Ford, Mrs. Edsel, 1948-1959 (Box 156, Folder 1572)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Goodwin, Philip, 1940-1958 (Box 156, Folder 1573)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Guggenheim, Mrs. Simon, 1949-1965 (Box 156, Folder 1574)
  Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Harrison, William K., 1950-1951 (Box 156, Folder 1575)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Husted, J. W. Husted, 1951 (Box 156, Folder 1576)
  Honorary and General Counsel.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Lasker, Albert D., 1948-1953 (Box 156, Folder 1577)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Levy, Mrs. David M., 1946-1958 (Box 156, Folder 1578)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Lewisohn, Sam A., 1948-1954 (Box 156, Folder 1579)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Luce, Mrs. Henry R., 1951 (Box 156, Folder 1580)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Miller, Mrs. G. MacCulloch, 1949 (Box 156, Folder 1581)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - MacDonald, R.H., 1948-1958 (Box 157, Folder 1582)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Marx, Mrs. Samuel A., 1953 (Box 157, Folder 1583)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Moe, Henry Allen, 1947-1963 (Box 157, Folder 1584)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Parkinson, Mrs. E. B., 1949-1969 (Box 157, Folder 1585)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Payson, Mrs. Charles S., 1948-1952 (Box 157, Folder 1586)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Phillips, Duncan, 1951 (Box 157, Folder 1587)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Rockefeller, David, 1947-1969 (Box 157, Folder 1588)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Rockefeller, Mrs. John D. 3rd, 1962-1971 (Box 157, Folder 1589)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1957-1970 (Box 157, Folder 1590)
  Resigned as President 6/53, resigned 12/58.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Ruml, Beardsley, 1949-1956 (Box 157, Folder 1591)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Sachs, J. Paul, 1950-1951 (Box 157, Folder 1592)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Senior, John L. Jr., 1951-1953 (Box 157, Folder 1593)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Shepard, Mrs. John S., 1951 (Box 157, Folder 1594)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Soby, James Thrall, 1951-1959 (Box 157, Folder 1595)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Warburg, Edward M. W., 1937-1958 (Box 157, Folder 1596)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Wheeler, Monroe, 1950-1968 (Box 157, Folder 1597)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Trustees - Individuals - Whitney, John Hay, 1946-1961 (Box 157, Folder 1598)
  Letters of appreciation to "Jock" for his generous support. Lists of attendance at Board Meetings.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Twentieth Century Italian Painting & Sculpture Exhibit, 1947-1950 (Box 157, Folder 1599)
  Letters of appreciation for interest in the exhibition. Correspondence re acquisition of paintings. Report on the Exhibition of 20th Century Italian Painting & Sculpture for the Museum of Modern Art. Letters of appointment to an Honorary Committee for the Italian Show. Letters from NAR requesting art works from their collectors for the exhibition and thanks. Letters of declination. Insurance correspondence.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Twentieth Century Italian Painting & Sculpture Exhibit - Honorary Committee, 1949 (Box 157, Folder 1600)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Twentieth Century Italian Painting & Sculpture Exhibit - Letters to be sent out, 1948-1949 (Box 157, Folder 1601)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Twentieth Century Italian Painting & Sculpture Exhibit - Letters to be sent out - Replies; Affirmative, 1949 (Box 157, Folder 1602)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Twentieth Century Italian Painting & Sculpture Exhibit - Letters to be sent out - Replies; Negative, 1949 (Box 157, Folder 1603)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Twentieth Century Italian Painting & Sculpture Exhibit - Sculpture Exhibition - Insurance, 1949 (Box 157, Folder 1604)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - UNESCO, 1946-1947 (Box 158, Folder 1605)
  Proposal that MoMA conduct international architects' competition for design of United Nations building. No development of idea in this file. Minutes of Board of Trustees: 1/10/46, 2/6/46, 2/28/46.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - UN Reception, 1946 (Box 158, Folder 1606)
  MoMA held open house for members of United Nations General Assembly. Photographs. Invitation list.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - United States Pavilion, Biennial, 1953-1954 (Box 158, Folder 1607)
  Letters of appreciation for MoMA's effort in Venice. Problem of Biennial in Venice.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Ulrich, Ione, 1946-1952 (Box 158, Folder 1608)
  Assistant Treasurer and Business Manager. Financial problems. Changes in accounting procedures. Elected Treasurer January, 1950. Resigned 1951.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - U.S.S.R., Exchange Visits, etc., 1956-1960 (Box 158, Folder 1609)
  Report: The Art Exhibit at The American Exhibition in Moscow, 1959. Rockefeller Brothers Fund contribution to MoMA for "Family of Man" photographic exhibit, part of U.S. exhibition in Moscow, 1949. Memos re Russia-MoMA relationships/possible artistic exchange with U.S.S.R. MoMA's proposal for interchange and request for a loan of the Soviet-owned Picassos.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Venezuela, 1947-1948, 1955 (Box 158, Folder 1610)
  Betancourt sends MoMA picture by Hector Poleo. MoMA lends picture for show in Venezuela. Brochure on Alexander Calder exhibit at Museo de Bellas Artes in Caracas, 1955.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Veterans' Art Center, 1946 (Box 158, Folder 1611)
  An experimental program at MoMA. Administration.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Visits to Private Collections, 1951 (Box 158, Folder 1612)
  Letters of appreciation for Mrs. NAR's opening of her apartment to contributing members of MoMA to view their collection.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - WPA Art Program, 1939 (Box 158, Folder 1613)
  MoMA sends $5,000 for WPA work.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Wheeler, Monroe, 1944-1969 (Box 158, Folder 1614)
  Correspondence with NAR. Publications, promotion, exhibitions.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Wheeler, Monroe - European Trip, 1948-1949 (Box 158, Folder 1615)
  NAR and Wheeler correspond re European Trip 1949.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Whitney Museum, Proposal, Property "21" etc., 1949-1952 (Box 159, Folder 1616)
  J. W. Husted correspondence re legal matters in Whitney Museum. Law Offices of Winthrop, Stimson, Putnam & Roberts. Whitney proposal re "21" Restaurant, etc. Whitney Museum to erect new building in garden of MoMA, 1949. Photostats of Blueprint of 21 West 53rd Street. Allocation of space on West 54th St. Property. Clippings.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Woodruff, Emily, 1948 (Box 159, Folder 1617)
  Connected with fund raising in MoMA.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Zeckendorf, William, 1948-1958 (Box 159, Folder 1618)
  Corporate contribution. Zeckendorf's association with MoMA.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - CTK Memos to NAR and David Rockefeller, 1953-1963 (Box 159, Folder 1619)
  Files of MoMA treasurer Charles T. Keppel from his office at 30 Rockefeller Plaza. Primarily carbon copies of his memos and letters to others on MoMA financial affairs.
  Memos, mostly to Louise Boyer, re Investment Committee meeting, budget.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - CTK Memos to R. d'Harnoncourt, 1957-1960 (Box 159, Folder 1620)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - CTK Memos to William Burden, 1956-1960 (Box 159, Folder 1621)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - By-Laws, 1931-1960 (Box 159, Folder 1622)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - CBS Contract re Family of Man, 1957-1959 (Box 159, Folder 1623)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Century Moving & Storage vs. MoMA, 1958-1959 (Box 159, Folder 1624)
  Arbitration about moving Japanese House from the New York waterfront to MoMA.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Contracts, 1957-1958 (Box 159, Folder 1625)
  With W. J. Burns Detective Agency and Local 32B of Building Service Union.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Fuller Construction Co., 1958-1960 (Box 159, Folder 1626)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Finance Committee, 1959-1961 (Box 159, Folder 1627)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Financial - Taxes, 1958-1961 (Box 160, Folder 1628)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Fire and Reconstruction, 1958-1961 (Box 160, Folder 1629)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Fire and Reconstruction - Clippings, 1958 (Box 160, Folder 1630)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Fund Raising Drive, 1959-1961 (Box 160, Folder 1631)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - International Council, 1957-1960 (Box 160, Folder 1632)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Investment Committee Minutes, 1959-1961 (Box 160, Folder 1633)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Legal, 1957-1961 (Box 160, Folder 1634)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Legal, 30% Tax Case, 1958-1961 (Box 160, Folder 1635)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Legal, Huntington, Hartford, 1958-1961 (Box 161, Folder 1636)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Mortgages, 1959-1960 (Box 161, Folder 1637)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Real Estate Memos, 1959-1961 (Box 161, Folder 1638)
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - Charles T. Keppel, Treasurer, Files - Union News Taxes, 1959-1961 (Box 161, Folder 1639)
- Museums - Museum of Navajo Ceremonial Art, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1946-1971 (Box 161, Folder 1640)
  NAR a guarantor member. Correspondence re activities of the Museum and NAR Annual Contributions; printed material.
- Museums - Museum of Personel - Cobb, Mabel, 1956-1959 (Box 161, Folder 1641)
  Invitation to become a trustee. Declined. Printed material. Appeals for aid.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - General, 1956-1972 (Box 161, Folder 1642)
  Re publications, acoustiguide, stationery, collections, standard invites. Robert Goldwater, Director. Clippings.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Miscellaneous (A-Z), 1957-1969 (Box 161, Folder 1643)
  General correspondence, comments, inquiries.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Acquisition Committee, Meetings, etc., 1969 (Box 161, Folder 1644)
  Functions of the Acquisitions Committee.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Administration Committee Minutes, 1963-1968 (Box 161, Folder 1645)
  Louise A. Boyer's copies of minutes. Southeby auction catalogue, 1965.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - African Sculpture From Museum Collection, 1966 (Box 162, Folder 1646)
  Checklist for the Press of Exhibition opening, 4/28/66.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Asmat Art Exhibitions, also re book, 1962-1971 (Box 162, Folder 1647)
  Martha Baird Rockefeller's $5,000,000 bequest to Museum of Primitive Art. Exhibit of Michael C. Rockefeller's art collection from the Asmat at the Phillips Exeter Academy, 1969. Exhibition of Michael's Asmat collection in Buffalo, 1967. Rene d'Harnoncourt work with exhibition space at MoMA, 1962. Michaels' book "Asmat." Exhibition at MoPA,1962. Clippings.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Asmat Art Exhibitions, also re book - Storage of Michael Rockefeller's Collection at Pocantico Hills Farm Barn, 1964-1965 (Box 162, Folder 1648)
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Attendance Records, 1957-1959 (Box 162, Folder 1649)
  Comparative attendance for 1957, 1958 and 1959. (Weekly and monthly attendance records discarded 7/24/73).
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Charter and By-Laws, 1954-1965 (Box 162, Folder 1650)
  Memos from C. T. Keppel. NAR contract with MoPA re loans of his works, 1957. Application to the New York State Regents for a change in the name of the Museum of Indigenous Art to the Museum of Primitive Art. Name changed as of January 1957. Museum of Indigenous Art By-Laws.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Collection, 1955-1971 (Box 162, Folder 1651)
  NAR's gifts to the collection of MoPA. Correspondence, loans. Press previews of exhibitions. List of objects in MoPA collection. List of gold objects offered by John Wise LTD. Prices of Polynesia - Fuller Collection.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Collection - Purchases, 1955-1971 (Box 162, Folder 1652)
  Prices and offers of Primitive Art. Album of Covarrubias includes drawings of possible purchases, lists of possible purchases from galleries.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Collection - Gifts, 1957-1968 (Box 162, Folder 1653)
  Gifts made to MoPA. NAR gave 55 Mexican Objects in 1964 and in 1969, a copy of 1935 Treaty which the U.S. did not sign, but which Latin America was using. Prices of some art work.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Collection - Guatemalan Mayan Stela, 1966-1970 (Box 163, Folder 1654)
  "Wall Street Journal" article by Bill Corley on smuggled art, re Guatemalan Stela.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Collection - NAR's contract with MoPA, September 18, 1957 (Box 163, Folder 1655)
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Collection - Auction of NAR & MoPA Art, 1967-1968 (Box 163, Folder 1656)
  Auction held by Parke Bernet Galleries. List of objects for proposed sale. Superior and general group. Auction catalogue.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Contributions - NAR, 1955-1971 (Box 163, Folder 1657)
  NAR's contributions, 1964-1971. NAR's gifts of objects for the collection. NAR gave his collection of primitive art to the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 5/9/69.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Contributions - NAR, 1955-1971 (Box 163, Folder 1658)
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Contributions - General, 1959-1971 (Box 163, Folder 1660)
  Charles T. Keppel's acknowledgements of various gifts to MoPA.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Contributions - Brill, William, 1964-1969 (Box 163, Folder 1661)
  Gifts to MoPA.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Exhibitions, 1957-1971 (Box 164, Folder 1662)
  Announcements of exhibitions. Correspondence re shows. Memo of agreement between NAR and A. Girard for designing and installing an exhibition of Mexican Folk Art turned down by NAR because it was too expensive. Covarrubias exhibit, 1963.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Exhibitions - Gerard, Alexander H., 1968-1969 (Box 164, Folder 1663)
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Exhibitions - Opening, 1957 (Box 164, Folder 1664)
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Exhibitions - Exhibition and Gift to Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1967-1969 (Box 164, Folder 1665)
  The Art of Oceania, Africa and the Americas Exhibit, publications and correspondence. Transfer of MoPA's collection to Metropolitan Museum of Art. The curatorial and professional staff of Art of Oceania, Africa and the Americas.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Exhibitions - Press Releases, Invitations, Clippings, 1957-1970 (Box 164, Folder 1666)
  Press previews, clippings. Invitation summary of the Third Exhibition, 10/57. "Arts" magazine article, 5/57, "Museum of Primitive Arts," by Milton Kramer. Exhibition requests.
- Museums - Museum of Primitive Art, 15 West 54th Street - Exhibitions - Requests for Exhibitions, 1962-1967 (Box 164, Folder 1667)
  Requests from various institutions.